<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[nrp blog]]></title>
  
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-11T18:41:15.909Z</updated>
  <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nrp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The First Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/11/The-First-Week/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/11/The-First-Week/</id>
    <published>2015-09-11T17:36:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-11T18:41:15.909Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vOKK9gC.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Ok, technically the First Week isn’t even over yet, but it’s Friday night and it feels like I’ve done so much already. I got into Kyiv on Tuesday midday after 21 hours of flights, or some stupid number of hours like that. That flight nonsense included a 6-hour layover in Dulles (which is much nicer than Reagan as far as airports go), an 8-hr transatlantic flight to Vienna sitting next to a German man who kept hogging the arm rests, and a 3km sprint from one Vienna terminal to another—seriously, that airport’s huge.</p>
<p>Arriving in Ukraine though I was surprised at just how much they’ve cleaned and classed up Boryspil. In 2007, when I was there last, it was just a tiny shade better than the super-old regional airports in other Ukrainian cities. This time though, the plane actually pulled up to one of those skybridge things so I didn’t have to go plane-&gt; staircase-&gt; tarmac-&gt; bus-&gt; airport. Ironically, in Vienna, the gate was on the ground floor and we had to take a bus across the tarmac to climb a metal staircase to get to the plane going to Kyiv.</p>
<p>Customs was a breeze and delightfully calm, especially compared to the explosion of people and sounds that was the part of the airport where people wait for arrivals. A huge throng of people, crushing their way through onlookers, valets, and loved ones trying to get their carts full of baggage to the outside doors. Predictably, I was confronted by the taxi-guy coordinator within about 18 seconds. I was going to take the bus—super cheap!—but there was already like 50 people in line for the next one and the taxi was only $22 so I figured why not. Taxi guy was super nice though, drove rather safely for a taxi driver, and got me to the airbnb place I’ve been staying at. This place has a loft in it, which is new for me, and the location’s pretty boss.</p>
<p>I did an airbnb because the registration process in Ukraine is stupid. Because of the visa I have to have, I have 45 days from arriving in country to register myself at a long-term address. So much of this week has been consumed by finding an apartment, which I was really just unable to do outside of Ukraine. The realty/rental company I’ve been working with though has been a peach, and they’ve done a great job, meaning I’ll be moving into my new apartment on Monday—yay! Both myself and Olga, from the rental company, were surprised to find something so quickly with an owner who was willing to actually register me, which for tax reasons, lots of people try to get out of. Except if I’m not registered, I invalidate my visa and therefore the terms of my grant, which would suck. But no worries, I got a great place and it’s all good. I’ll put pics of it in the next post.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/lP5XiJ2.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Zoloti Vorota, the Golden Gates. Above is Maidan Nezalezhnosti.</small></em></p>
<h1 id="Kyiv">Kyiv</h1><p>Kyiv is a great city. It’s got lots of wonderful things going for it, and the part of the city I’m in right now—near Zoloti Vorota—is pretty much smack in the middle. Cobblestone streets, old buildings with cool facades, museums and monuments everywhere, underground shopping malls, multiple coffee trucks per block—it’s got it all. What I’m most impressed with though is how <em>safe</em> the city feels. There’s also more cars and more people and more diversity and more dirt (but less stray dogs and beggars), but everyone has their smartphones out and so many people are wearing backpacks—two things that I really didn’t see 8-10 years ago. The phones, sure, didn’t have the same market penetration they have now, but even so, there just seems to be this feeling that the city’s safer.</p>
<p>I’ve also been doing <em>so much</em> walking. A benefit of city living, for sure. I’ve got my little jawbone fitness tracker guy and I’m averaging almost 20k steps a day. My feet and legs are still trying to get used to all of it, but it’s all good. I even decided to walk down to Podil yesterday morning, since it would’ve taken the same amount of time to walk to the metro, ride the metro, then walk to my destination. Podil, if you’re unfamiliar with Kyiv, is one of the oldest parts of the city, down in the lowlands between hills where the center of town is and the Dnipro. It’s also where Kyiv-Mohyla Academy is—one of the universities I’ll be working with—the Chornobyl museum, and my new apartment are.</p>
<p>It’s also nice because it’s flat.</p>
<p>Right now, at this airbnb place, I’m at the bottom of a valley so either way I want to head out from my apartment to downtown or to the metro is uphill. Not only is it uphill, but one of those hills is the highest part of the city. It’s rough if I need to head north. But cool though, because at the top of that hill is St Sophia’s and St Andrews, which are both beautiful. Kyiv, man, it’s got everything.</p>
<p>All in all, it’s been a crazy few days re-adjusting back to Ukrainian life. Language is probably the biggest hurdle there. I’ve felt all kinds of dumb trying to get my brain and mouth to switch over to Ukrainian and/or Russian, and the struggle is real. I’m trying not to take the weird looks I get personally though, and each day I feel like I’ve gotten better at it. In no time I’ll be up to snuff again though, no worries.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vOKK9gC.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Ok, technically the First Week isn’t even over yet, but it’s Friday night and it]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Kyiv" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Kyiv/"/>
    
      <category term="Update" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Update/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Orientation]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/08/12/Orientation/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/08/12/Orientation/</id>
    <published>2015-08-12T11:29:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-08-12T12:12:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/EaC1X04.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>At the end of July I attended the Fulbright Pre-Departure Orientation (PDO) in DC. It was a nice gig, the State Department (I think) paid for the flight and hotel, and we had a nice time at the orientation getting to know each other. This was the first time I was in DC, too, so I tried to make it out to as much as I could see in the small amount of free time I had.</p>
<h1 id="PDO_and_the_Group">PDO and the Group</h1><p>The group of students going to Ukraine seems like a good one, if kinda small: three English teachers (going to Chernivtsi, Vinnitsya, and Zhytomyr) and six researchers (all but one going to Kyiv). I was actually surprised at how young the group is—all three of the ETAs and two of the student researchers have graduated college in the past couple years. There was one guy who couldn’t make it, but besides him, there were only two others who were PhD students/candidates. There are also a bunch of scholars (I think all of them are faculty at some uni or another), but we didn’t get to know them that well.</p>
<p>It was also kind of odd that of the eight of us students that attended PDO, only one other besides myself wasn’t from or going to school in New England. Maine was heavily represented, which seems quite odd.</p>
<p>The orientation itself was just fine, though it seemed to be geared more towards people that had never left the country before, which makes sense since you gotta hit the lowest common denominator in a group as large as this one. I didn’t bother counting, but it looked like there were a good 400 Fulbrighters going off to countries in the East Europe and Eurasia region. Like any conference, there were some good panels and some lame panels. I’ll spare you the play-by-play of events, but here were some choice highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>the head hotel staff guy when calling everyone to order would play a golden xylophone to get us to be quiet and sit</li>
<li>the view from our room was pretty cool (see pic below), this weird indoor courtyard deal</li>
<li>Anders Aslund made some controversial remarks and got slammed for them in the first question in the Q&amp;A section</li>
<li>only one other person besides me in the group has no Ukrainian ancestry</li>
<li>only one person in the group has not been to Ukraine before</li>
<li>AIPAC was also having a convention the same time as us</li>
<li>the hotel food was serviceable but overall underwhelming, except for the desserts the first night </li>
<li>the guy giving a presentation on issues for LGBTQI people going to the region was pretty insensitive, contradictory, and troubling—his whole message was basically “just go back in the closet for 9 months” but at the end said “now I’m not telling you to back into the closet…”</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/c0XGb3d.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h1 id="Washington_DC">Washington DC</h1><p>Reagan Airport was my initial point of contact to the city, and boy is that architecture a product of its times. Cool-looking though. I opted to take the metro into the city and I quite liked it, even though I went the wrong way on the blue line for a stop. The cars on the train though were in rougher shape than the ones in Chicago that I saw. I couldn’t help but notice just how closely Bethesda modeled their Fallout 3 subway stations after their real-life counterparts.</p>
<p>After dinner, a bunch of us walked down to the Washington Monument as it was getting dark. It was fine. What did strike me though was just how much acreage is dedicated to parks and monuments. When on the last day we went to the White House, the WW2 Memorial, the Lincoln Memorial, and the places in between I was surprised at just how much room there was in between each thing. The winner of coolest/best memorial in terms of aesthetics? Korean War.</p>
<p>I also got to meet up with my cousin-in-law Scott as he was getting off work in some State Department office where he does something along the lines of coordinating AIDS relief efforts and aid. Had some tasty froyo, which was nice because it was sweltering. I didn’t realize it until I saw the ground flying into the airport, but DC’s just a giant swamp and it sure felt like it.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/EaC1X04.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>At the end of July I attended the Fulbright Pre-Departure Orientation (PDO) in D]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Fulbright program" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Fulbright-program/"/>
    
      <category term="group" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/group/"/>
    
      <category term="Update" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Update/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/07/09/first-post/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/07/09/first-post/</id>
    <published>2015-07-09T16:41:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-09T21:25:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dLWnVYq.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h1 id="Might_as_well_blog">Might as well blog</h1><p>It’s been a while since I’ve maintained a blog with any kind of regularity, but my upcoming Fulbright to Ukraine has prompted me to start up a new one. For those of you who, like my parents, would worry without any regular updates, look! You can get your updates here. And without the mass group email.</p>
<p>I’ll still be active on twitter, but this medium allows for longer posts with more pictures and stuff. Consider it a facebook replacement that you don’t have to feel obligated to like every post or picture I put up.</p>
<p>As far as the frequency of posts, I want to put up a new one every week or so, but I imagine that occasionally I won’t be in a place with reliable internet (or that I really just didn’t do anything interesting that week).</p>
<p>But if you want to contact me while I’m in Ukraine, you should check out the <a href="/about/index.html">About</a> page that has all my contact info.</p>
<p><em><small>The picture’s one I took when living in Ivano-Frankivsk in 2007</small></em></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dLWnVYq.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h1 id="Might_as_well_blog">Might as well blog</h1><p>It’s been a while since I’ve ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="Information" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Information/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
