<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[nrp blog]]></title>
  
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-30T11:43:03.646Z</updated>
  <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nrp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Photo Dump 2: Chornobyl and Slavutych]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/11/30/Photo-Dump-2-Chornobyl-and-Slavutych/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/11/30/Photo-Dump-2-Chornobyl-and-Slavutych/</id>
    <published>2015-11-30T10:36:06.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-30T11:43:03.646Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, I took a tour of Chornobyl with some friends. It was the first time I had been there, and I took a bunch of pictures. I was really self-conscious of not wanting to take the same photos of the same things that everyone else does (especially since most of the tours do mostly the same stuff all the time). So hopefully these will at the very least be fresh.</p>
<p>It was weird though being in Pripyat, a place I’ve read about and seen a bunch of pictures of. The lived experience added new layers of understanding.</p>
<p>A couple days after returning from Chornobyl, I went to Slavutych to check out the city archives and make some contacts there. Slavutych was built as a replacement city for Pripyat, a place to house the workers that were liquidating and still running the power plant (the last reactor wasn’t disabled until 2002). Slavutych is an almost surreal city—the last planned city the USSR built, the youngest city in Ukraine, and almost completely unchanged since the late 80s. The city is dying as work wraps up on building the new sarcophagus, the New Safe Confinement structure, because when that’s done, the last big employer moves out. Already it’s a city of children and the elderly, since everyone in the middle moves away for school, work, or really any other excuse they can find. There’s a palpable feeling that the end is nigh for Slavutych, though earlier this month, a new mayor was elected on a platform of finding a way to keep the city alive. Fun fact: he’s only the 2nd mayor Slavutych has ever had—the first one served for 25 years and retired in April of this year.</p>
<p>There are a few videos embedded like gifs below, I hope they work.</p>
<h2 id="Chornobyl,_Pripyat,_and_the_Zone">Chornobyl, Pripyat, and the Zone</h2><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dvuH5AY.jpg?1" alt="The obligatory entrance selfie in front of the border station to get into the 30km zone"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/2Ninfhc.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/fYAIFGH.jpg?1" alt="It&#39;s hard to see, but in the center there&#39;s a sign marking the town of Chornobyl that has been crossed out, as many of the towns and villages were when they were evacuated"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/7lxoGq7.jpg?1" alt="The Wormwood Institute in Chornobyl"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/YCHjFiu.jpg?1" alt="Monument to the firefighteres and first responders the night of the explosion. The plaque says &quot;To those who saved the world.&quot;"></p>
<video width="653" height="367" autoplay loop muted markdown="1"><br><source src="http://giant.gfycat.com/EnchantedNewHumpbackwhale.webm" type="video/webm" markdown="1"><br></video>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/gbRIrhM.jpg?1" alt="The monument right in front of the power plant, visible in the background. To the right, off camera, is the new sarcofagus"></p>
<video width="653" height="367" autoplay loop muted markdown="1"><br><source src="http://giant.gfycat.com/ChiefQuarrelsomeCrane.webm" type="video/webm" markdown="1"><br></video>

<p><small>Driving around Pripyat</small></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/wj845IG.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/edjkXJs.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/y96VIZk.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/BcTQn46.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/zMx4XJI.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/tvbQAuV.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/7D1UDK7.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/j6o4CSo.jpg?1" alt="This is the exterior to the sports complex by the school"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/wfbwGeQ.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/rnXMFCh.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/6vRS4cu.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/zqRVvuH.jpg?1" alt="A hallway in the school"></p>
<p><video width="653" height="367" autoplay loop muted markdown="1"></video></p>
<p><source src="http://giant.gfycat.com/WellgroomedDelectableAcornweevil.webm" type="video/webm" markdown="1"><br><br><small>Leaving Pripyat through some backcountry roads</small></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/XOJXAvK.jpg?1" alt="This is the Russian Woodpecker, a giant antenna array that was a Soviet secret--on maps this area was designated a summer camp"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/1xBkKSJ.jpg?1" alt="It&#39;s hard to see the scale of the Woodpecker, but this one gives some idea of it"></p>
<h2 id="Slavutych">Slavutych</h2><p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Z5JWfqu.jpg?1" alt="The 3rd original plan of the city of Slavutych. The 4th was the one that was actually built, though the differences between these two versions are only the placement of some buildings. That said, the tall central building was never built, and the lake in the central park is a skate park"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/nGaYJFu.jpg?1" alt="Cool stained glass panels in the Slavutych city museum"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/kgKEm3M.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/lJrFWOy.jpg?1" alt="Radiation detector"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/0ciNMuC.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/kwEs0UV.jpg?1" alt="Old Tallinn, one of only 3 restaurants in the city"></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ldYVPE9.jpg?1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/S3nAiFL.jpg?1" alt="The Angel of Slavutych"></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Last week, I took a tour of Chornobyl with some friends. It was the first time I had been there, and I took a bunch of pictures. I was re]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Chornobyl" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Chornobyl/"/>
    
      <category term="research" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/research/"/>
    
      <category term="Photos" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Photos/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Getting Cold]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/10/14/Getting-Cold/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/10/14/Getting-Cold/</id>
    <published>2015-10-14T20:29:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-14T21:17:15.815Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/mUrff1q.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p><small><em>Andriy, Lyosha, me, and Sasha at the Ukraine-Spain game</em></small></p>
<p>So much for keeping this a weekly thing, huh?</p>
<p>October has brought a number of things with it, including a pretty long cold spell here. Though I say cold knowing that it’s only going to get colder and this 27-50 temp range we’ve had the past couple weeks will seem nice and toasty in a few months.</p>
<p>But.</p>
<p>(Before I get into the reason for that but up there, I have to warn you—don’t freak out, there’s nothing you or really anyone can do in this particular situation. Sufficiently spooked? Doot doot good!)</p>
<p>But.</p>
<p>The thing is, when it’s crazy cold in a couple months, the heat in my building will be on. Actually, it’s scheduled to turn on tomorrow. Rumors cut through the conversations of Kievans everywhere that in some places in the city the heat would be turned on earlier than than traditional date of October 15, and in the center of center—you know, where all the fancy people live in their fancy apartments—the heat’s actually been on for a couple of days. We thought we’d get lucky here in Podil, but no such luck. And as an added bonus, once the building heat turns on (which takes the form of wall-mounted radiators), then I’ll also get hot water running through <em>all</em> the pipes in the apartment so I can have longer than 2 mins of hot water in the shower from my teeny tiny boiler.</p>
<p>Here’s the thing about stuff like this in Ukraine—energy is a big ole deal. Has been since independence. Most of the gas and oil comes from Russia, which has all kinds of problems. Like when Russia regularly threatens to shut off the pipes. Or when Russia invades the east of Ukraine, shutting off the country from all of coal mines and reserves in the Donbas. Also, as part of its Soviet legacy, energy costs have been heavily subsidized by the government to the tune of 90% in recent years. Which is great if you’re a resident, but sucky if you’re the nigh-perpetually-bankrupt government. There’s been all kinds of attempted magic with getting energy from multiple other sources, but one of the tricks they’re implementing is slowly rolling back that subsidy so that in a few years time, it will be gone completely and the burden of paying for fuel will fall to the people.</p>
<p>This persistent energy crisis is also a big part of the reason why the vast majority (read: non-Chornobyl) of Ukraine’s nuclear power plants are still churning.</p>
<p>On that note, an update on my research activities: there have been two major developments. The first is that my advisor at the Institute of Sociology at the National Academy of Sciences is the former director of a Chornobyl research group that did systematic monitoring of the social effects of the disaster from 1995 to 2007 (when the govt decided it couldn’t fund the project any more). She’s been awesome and actually gave me (as in gifted) extra copies of all of their publications! Downside: I’ve got a few thousand pages of material to go through lol. The other thing is finally getting access to the Communist Party archive of Soviet Ukraine. Another embarrassment of riches here: they have a rather decent finding guide for Chornobyl-related documents in the archive, which definitely cuts down on the searching time, and now I just have to wade through hundreds of documents to find the ones I need. It’s daunting, but also great. Archival research can be pretty fun—a slow, painstaking fun maybe—especially when you find cool, unexpected items.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/tp6PKQq.jpg" alt=""><br><small><em>A winter corset made of dog hair with leg warmers made from camels.</em></small></p>
<p>This week, as you can see in the pic at the top of the post, I had an old, good friend (Andriy) come into town with a bunch of his friends from Lutsk to come watch the Ukrainian national team play Spain. Even though Ukraine lost, it was still a pretty impressive game and everybody had a lot of fun. Because it was a euro game (as in, a qualifying game for next year’s Euro Cup), that meant the game was on euro time, so it started at 9:30pm local. Even so, Olympiskiy Stadium was all the way full. I was surprised I remembered as much as I did of the Ukrainian national anthem.</p>
<p>It was also really cold, keeping with today’s theme.</p>
<p>But it was a lot of fun to see Andriy after 8 or so years. Funny how fast that flew by. In that time, each of us got married, he’s got a 4 year old daughter now, I’m in a PhD program, and he’s been playing with a traveling theater group for the past 7 years in his spare time. Shout out time: the group’s called <a href="http://www.garmyder.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Garmyder</a>. Three of his bros that came out with him to the game are also in the theater with him.</p>
<p>Here’s a list of other things I’ve been up to:</p>
<ul>
<li>bought some slippers and a wool blanket</li>
<li>did laundry</li>
<li>finally completely unpacked (ha!)</li>
<li>picked up a vyshyvanka to wear to <a href="http://www.ukma.edu.ua/index.php/about-us/istoriya-akademiji/mohyliantsi-400-rokiv" target="_blank" rel="external">Kyiv-Mohyla’s 400-year anniversary gala</a> tomorrow that Pres. Poroshenko will be at (!)</li>
<li>completed Katie’s Little Women doll collection as a surprise</li>
<li>walked probably over a hundred miles in the past 2 weeks (no joke)</li>
<li>crocheted a hat</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/mUrff1q.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p><small><em>Andriy, Lyosha, me, and Sasha at the Ukraine-Spain game</em></small><]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Kyiv" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Kyiv/"/>
    
      <category term="research" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/research/"/>
    
      <category term="Update" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Update/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Photo Dump 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/29/Photo-Dump-1/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/29/Photo-Dump-1/</id>
    <published>2015-09-28T23:29:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-30T06:38:56.365Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been taking a bunch of photos and not all of them make it into my posts. So here’s a bunch all in one dump. Page is probably going to take a while to load, fyi. These are in no particular order and will have only the barest of captions. Hit me up on twitter <a href="http://twitter.com/ghostlenin" target="_blank" rel="external">@ghostlenin</a> if you have questions or whatever. Click to make em bigger.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/UFifa6L.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>The delicious Atlanta Burger at 3B</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Fd9DQDk.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Shashlik at Hydropark</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/GfuEEUc.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Graffiti and urban decay at the far end of the paintball field, Hydropark</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/gyoWfeS.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Scene out the back of a restaurant on a small tributary of the Dnipro</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Ptk4AG2.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>On the bridge at Hydropark looking at the river. Kids were jumping off the bridge for fun, dodging motorboats and jetskis</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/BNaScYi.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Monument to Princess Olha in front of the Diplomatic Academy across from St Michael’s</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/typ45kA.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>The Dnipro from the boat cruise</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/txQReoE.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Stylized shot of a statue at the chapel on campus at Kyiv-Mohyla</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/H8mLbiT.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>An actual burrito. Real(ish) Mexican food. Was pretty good, too</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/d8wkqAH.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>The huge light-up tequila bottle at the Mexican joint</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/OUNqKyq.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>The entrance to St Sophia’s</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/t1NGHh4.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Statue of Bohdan Khmelnitsky across from the one above</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/DBmJFfL.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Small statue of a Cossack killing the two-headed dragon of Russia</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/TaCrY15.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Statue of Lysenko outside his opera theater</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Bq4MN4V.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Weird southwest scene at Dream Town 2, a too-big mall</small></em></p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/QFzduZU.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>The Grecoroman installation at Dream Town 2</small></em></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I’ve been taking a bunch of photos and not all of them make it into my posts. So here’s a bunch all in one dump. Page is probably going t]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Kyiv" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Kyiv/"/>
    
      <category term="food" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/food/"/>
    
      <category term="Photos" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Photos/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Orientation 2 and Brazil]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/28/Orientation-and-Brazil/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/28/Orientation-and-Brazil/</id>
    <published>2015-09-28T08:29:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-30T06:45:28.360Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/5oWjH4J.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Well, first off, I meant to write something last week. I really did, I promise. Lots to catch up on, a real updatey-update.</p>
<p>First things first then, I guess. I moved into my new apartment in Podil, once the historic market quarter and port of old Kyiv, now the cool, trendy part of town. Kyiv-Mohyla and the Ukrainian National Chornobyl Museum are blocks away, and I’m a 4 minute walk to the metro. My neighborhood is quiet and I have everything I need nearby. Sure, the apartment’s a studio on the 4th floor with no lift, but it fits my needs and I can’t ask for a better location. Huge shout out to <a href="http://teren.kiev.ua" target="_blank" rel="external">Teren Plus</a> for being great. The pic up top is the view from the window.</p>
<p>Moving in to this place though was not without some hassle. Like having to call the maintenance guy the 2nd day because the hot water was doing weird things (turns out the lines were switched going into the tiny boiler) or having to buy pillows and a sheet set—all kinds of new words I had to learn. There is a random assortment of kitchen things—like 6 plates, 4 bowls, 3 large plates, 5 small plates, 2 tea cups, one mug, and one other matching ceramic piece I can’t figure out what it is—but was lacking some things, like a sharp knife, a skillet, and a cutting board. Most of these things were easily taken care of with some trips to the huge Petrivka bazaar, MegaMarket, and the local grocer, but man, the hassle.</p>
<p>Speaking of, and to the Brazil part of the title, Ukrainian bureaucracy is suffocating. All this running around. Regulations upon regulations. Everyone knows it too, but what can you do? You play the game to get th things done you need. These troubles in particular stem from the registration process. Allow me to explain.</p>
<p>If you’re in Ukraine for more than 3 months, you need 1) a visa and 2) to register. The visa process is stupid in itself, requiring a letter of invitation from a university, a letter affirming my reason for being there from Fulbright, a letter from the Ministry of Education, a set of photos, and my passport. The registration process needs even more things. First, I needed a suite of documents similar to those for the visa, but just different enough to require new ones that of course all have to be the originals and notarized—plus the new addition of a receipt of purchase of mandatory Ukrainian insurance. That meant another letter from Fulbright, a letter of affiliation from Kyiv-Mohyla, and a new letter from the Ministry of Education. With these in hand, plus more photos, Christina, Zoe, and I (the 3 Mohylantsi Fulbrighters) went with Olya and Natalia (from the KMA office of international students) to the immigration office. This office was an hour-long bus ride that went across the river and into the almost-suburbs. To get to the immigration office though, you had to walk about 15 minutes off any roads into the spaces between buildings before coming to the squat govt office. We got there at 9:30 to line up in advance. The office didn’t open until 10, but you had to get there before it opened to get in line to be early enough to get onto the list to be seen that day. When our collective turn came up, Christina went with Olya and Natalia into the room with the immigration officer, but they were only there for about 5 minutes before they were yelled at to leave because we didn’t bring enough pictures of each of us. Or more precisely: the immigration office website said to bring 2 each but they had changed the regulations to 4 without telling anyone. So we had to forfeit our place in line to walk out of the concrete jungle, find a place that would take and print our pictures, and then walk back, only to wait in line again. In all, what should have taken 30 mins, minus travel time, ended taking up 5 hours total.</p>
<p>And then, to make it all the better, all of this was only a preliminary hearing of sorts for the immigration officer to make sure we had all the right forms. Tomorrow I have to give my passport to KMA so they can go back to immigration with all the forms the next day in order to receive my temporary registration card.</p>
<p>Because all this nonsense so far is just for a temporary registration card. Which, after you get one, can be turned into an actual registration card within 45 days if you take your passport, temp reg, landlord or -lady, the original ownership document of the apartment, and enough cash to cover the registration tax down to your local friendly registration office (Zhek). So when I get my temp reg on Friday—assuming of course that everything goes cleanly in the black box of the immigration office bureaucracy—then I can take a trip with my landlady to the same office you go to get marriage licenses and pay your gas bill so I can live here legally and have my single-entry visa turned into a multi-entry visa. Braziiiiiiil.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/6FoIfOW.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Here’s a picture of the Red Building of Shevchenko National University at night to break things up.</p>
<p>Want some more Brazil? Okay, here’s a story from today.</p>
<p>I had a meeting scheduled with my in-country advisor at Kyiv-Mohyla today. She’s been working on a list of authors and contacts for me to help in my research, which I’m super grateful for. I also emailed her about writing some letters of introduction for the archives I want to visit, but never heard anything back, but since I was meeting her today I figured I’d just ask her about it rather than sending another email. So I went to the building at 1:30, went up to the 2nd floor, saw my advisor in the hall. She comes up, says (in Ukrainian, mind) “Hi! I got your email about archive letters, but didn’t see it until Friday. I wrote them but they won’t be ready to pick up until tomorrow because I had them printed on official letterhead, so let’s just meet at this time again tomorrow.” I was cool with that because hey, letters. Since I had some time to fill, I figured I’d just go drop off my passport to Olya for registration even though it wasn’t due until tomorrow. I go up there, no Olya. The sign on the door says it’s her lunch hour. I say well okay I’ll come back at 3 when the lunch hour is over. So I go to the library (that you can check books out at, but then can’t remove them from the building) and my laptop won’t connect to the internet. No idea why. Getting limited connection errors and then it just straight up refuses to connect after working for about 5 mins. So I get done what I need to (which was find the exact numbers of the laws that relate to Chornobyl in this book of laws so I could looks the laws up online later) and at 3 go back to Olya’s office. She’s still not there, but one of the Fulbright scholar ladies is up there so we chat, and she says Olya isn’t in today at all. Very frustrating, but since I have to be up there tomorrow anyway for my rescheduled meeting, it’s all good.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/jzt2IsS.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Then there was the In-Country Orientation. Two days of mandatory fun!</p>
<p>It wasn’t all that bad actually. Day 1 was in the US Embassy, where they confiscated all electronics so I have no pics. A bunch of people talked to us about orientationy things and we asked a bunch of questions, including a lengthy and ridiculous discussion on the fact that in the <em>extremely unlikely event</em> that the embassy decides all Americans need to be evac’d, no they would not foot the bill, we’d have to pay ourselves. It started off with a joke that was taken seriously and the whole conversation just went off the rails.</p>
<p>At the end of Day 1 we met up for a reception at the old embassy, which has been renamed and repurposed as America House, where all kinds of cultural events happen. We were told we can also use the premises for whatever we need, like interviews and whatnot, which is very generous and cool. It was fun having the larger Fulbrighter community all hanging out in one place, since all the non-Kyivers came in for the orientation.</p>
<p>On Day 2 though the everyone-hanging-in-one-place thing was taken to its uncomfortable extreme. It started off well enough, with 3 speakers at the Fulbright office—one on his <a href="http://rany.com.ua" target="_blank" rel="external">photojournalism project with wounded Ukrainian soldiers</a>, another on his upcoming book about Maidan—excuse me, the Revolution of Dignity—as a tripartite revolution of a kind hitherto unseen, and the third on the state of tv journalism in the country. But then, we all got on a bus to get on a boat to take a 4-hour cruise down the Dnipro.</p>
<p>In case you didn’t know, 4 hours is a loooooooong time to be stuck on a boat. I mean, I talked to cool people about cool things, but at about 2.5 hours in, EVERYONE was exhausted. It was hot, humid, and we were trapped in a room. Sure the room was floating on a river, but we were trapped nonetheless. Perhaps describing it that way makes it sound worse than it was though, but like in any situation, you try to make the best of it and I think everybody had a pretty good time overall.</p>
<p>Afterward though, a small group of us got together for some Georgian food, so it ended on a high note.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/5oWjH4J.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Well, first off, I meant to write something last week. I really did, I promise. ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Fulbright program" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Fulbright-program/"/>
    
      <category term="Kyiv" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Kyiv/"/>
    
      <category term="group" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/group/"/>
    
      <category term="Update" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Update/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The First Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/11/The-First-Week/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/09/11/The-First-Week/</id>
    <published>2015-09-11T17:36:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-11T18:41:15.909Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vOKK9gC.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Ok, technically the First Week isn’t even over yet, but it’s Friday night and it feels like I’ve done so much already. I got into Kyiv on Tuesday midday after 21 hours of flights, or some stupid number of hours like that. That flight nonsense included a 6-hour layover in Dulles (which is much nicer than Reagan as far as airports go), an 8-hr transatlantic flight to Vienna sitting next to a German man who kept hogging the arm rests, and a 3km sprint from one Vienna terminal to another—seriously, that airport’s huge.</p>
<p>Arriving in Ukraine though I was surprised at just how much they’ve cleaned and classed up Boryspil. In 2007, when I was there last, it was just a tiny shade better than the super-old regional airports in other Ukrainian cities. This time though, the plane actually pulled up to one of those skybridge things so I didn’t have to go plane-&gt; staircase-&gt; tarmac-&gt; bus-&gt; airport. Ironically, in Vienna, the gate was on the ground floor and we had to take a bus across the tarmac to climb a metal staircase to get to the plane going to Kyiv.</p>
<p>Customs was a breeze and delightfully calm, especially compared to the explosion of people and sounds that was the part of the airport where people wait for arrivals. A huge throng of people, crushing their way through onlookers, valets, and loved ones trying to get their carts full of baggage to the outside doors. Predictably, I was confronted by the taxi-guy coordinator within about 18 seconds. I was going to take the bus—super cheap!—but there was already like 50 people in line for the next one and the taxi was only $22 so I figured why not. Taxi guy was super nice though, drove rather safely for a taxi driver, and got me to the airbnb place I’ve been staying at. This place has a loft in it, which is new for me, and the location’s pretty boss.</p>
<p>I did an airbnb because the registration process in Ukraine is stupid. Because of the visa I have to have, I have 45 days from arriving in country to register myself at a long-term address. So much of this week has been consumed by finding an apartment, which I was really just unable to do outside of Ukraine. The realty/rental company I’ve been working with though has been a peach, and they’ve done a great job, meaning I’ll be moving into my new apartment on Monday—yay! Both myself and Olga, from the rental company, were surprised to find something so quickly with an owner who was willing to actually register me, which for tax reasons, lots of people try to get out of. Except if I’m not registered, I invalidate my visa and therefore the terms of my grant, which would suck. But no worries, I got a great place and it’s all good. I’ll put pics of it in the next post.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/lP5XiJ2.jpg" alt=""><br><em><small>Zoloti Vorota, the Golden Gates. Above is Maidan Nezalezhnosti.</small></em></p>
<h1 id="Kyiv">Kyiv</h1><p>Kyiv is a great city. It’s got lots of wonderful things going for it, and the part of the city I’m in right now—near Zoloti Vorota—is pretty much smack in the middle. Cobblestone streets, old buildings with cool facades, museums and monuments everywhere, underground shopping malls, multiple coffee trucks per block—it’s got it all. What I’m most impressed with though is how <em>safe</em> the city feels. There’s also more cars and more people and more diversity and more dirt (but less stray dogs and beggars), but everyone has their smartphones out and so many people are wearing backpacks—two things that I really didn’t see 8-10 years ago. The phones, sure, didn’t have the same market penetration they have now, but even so, there just seems to be this feeling that the city’s safer.</p>
<p>I’ve also been doing <em>so much</em> walking. A benefit of city living, for sure. I’ve got my little jawbone fitness tracker guy and I’m averaging almost 20k steps a day. My feet and legs are still trying to get used to all of it, but it’s all good. I even decided to walk down to Podil yesterday morning, since it would’ve taken the same amount of time to walk to the metro, ride the metro, then walk to my destination. Podil, if you’re unfamiliar with Kyiv, is one of the oldest parts of the city, down in the lowlands between hills where the center of town is and the Dnipro. It’s also where Kyiv-Mohyla Academy is—one of the universities I’ll be working with—the Chornobyl museum, and my new apartment are.</p>
<p>It’s also nice because it’s flat.</p>
<p>Right now, at this airbnb place, I’m at the bottom of a valley so either way I want to head out from my apartment to downtown or to the metro is uphill. Not only is it uphill, but one of those hills is the highest part of the city. It’s rough if I need to head north. But cool though, because at the top of that hill is St Sophia’s and St Andrews, which are both beautiful. Kyiv, man, it’s got everything.</p>
<p>All in all, it’s been a crazy few days re-adjusting back to Ukrainian life. Language is probably the biggest hurdle there. I’ve felt all kinds of dumb trying to get my brain and mouth to switch over to Ukrainian and/or Russian, and the struggle is real. I’m trying not to take the weird looks I get personally though, and each day I feel like I’ve gotten better at it. In no time I’ll be up to snuff again though, no worries.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vOKK9gC.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Ok, technically the First Week isn’t even over yet, but it’s Friday night and it]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Kyiv" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Kyiv/"/>
    
      <category term="Update" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Update/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Orientation]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/08/12/Orientation/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/08/12/Orientation/</id>
    <published>2015-08-12T11:29:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-08-12T12:12:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/EaC1X04.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>At the end of July I attended the Fulbright Pre-Departure Orientation (PDO) in DC. It was a nice gig, the State Department (I think) paid for the flight and hotel, and we had a nice time at the orientation getting to know each other. This was the first time I was in DC, too, so I tried to make it out to as much as I could see in the small amount of free time I had.</p>
<h1 id="PDO_and_the_Group">PDO and the Group</h1><p>The group of students going to Ukraine seems like a good one, if kinda small: three English teachers (going to Chernivtsi, Vinnitsya, and Zhytomyr) and six researchers (all but one going to Kyiv). I was actually surprised at how young the group is—all three of the ETAs and two of the student researchers have graduated college in the past couple years. There was one guy who couldn’t make it, but besides him, there were only two others who were PhD students/candidates. There are also a bunch of scholars (I think all of them are faculty at some uni or another), but we didn’t get to know them that well.</p>
<p>It was also kind of odd that of the eight of us students that attended PDO, only one other besides myself wasn’t from or going to school in New England. Maine was heavily represented, which seems quite odd.</p>
<p>The orientation itself was just fine, though it seemed to be geared more towards people that had never left the country before, which makes sense since you gotta hit the lowest common denominator in a group as large as this one. I didn’t bother counting, but it looked like there were a good 400 Fulbrighters going off to countries in the East Europe and Eurasia region. Like any conference, there were some good panels and some lame panels. I’ll spare you the play-by-play of events, but here were some choice highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>the head hotel staff guy when calling everyone to order would play a golden xylophone to get us to be quiet and sit</li>
<li>the view from our room was pretty cool (see pic below), this weird indoor courtyard deal</li>
<li>Anders Aslund made some controversial remarks and got slammed for them in the first question in the Q&amp;A section</li>
<li>only one other person besides me in the group has no Ukrainian ancestry</li>
<li>only one person in the group has not been to Ukraine before</li>
<li>AIPAC was also having a convention the same time as us</li>
<li>the hotel food was serviceable but overall underwhelming, except for the desserts the first night </li>
<li>the guy giving a presentation on issues for LGBTQI people going to the region was pretty insensitive, contradictory, and troubling—his whole message was basically “just go back in the closet for 9 months” but at the end said “now I’m not telling you to back into the closet…”</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/c0XGb3d.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h1 id="Washington_DC">Washington DC</h1><p>Reagan Airport was my initial point of contact to the city, and boy is that architecture a product of its times. Cool-looking though. I opted to take the metro into the city and I quite liked it, even though I went the wrong way on the blue line for a stop. The cars on the train though were in rougher shape than the ones in Chicago that I saw. I couldn’t help but notice just how closely Bethesda modeled their Fallout 3 subway stations after their real-life counterparts.</p>
<p>After dinner, a bunch of us walked down to the Washington Monument as it was getting dark. It was fine. What did strike me though was just how much acreage is dedicated to parks and monuments. When on the last day we went to the White House, the WW2 Memorial, the Lincoln Memorial, and the places in between I was surprised at just how much room there was in between each thing. The winner of coolest/best memorial in terms of aesthetics? Korean War.</p>
<p>I also got to meet up with my cousin-in-law Scott as he was getting off work in some State Department office where he does something along the lines of coordinating AIDS relief efforts and aid. Had some tasty froyo, which was nice because it was sweltering. I didn’t realize it until I saw the ground flying into the airport, but DC’s just a giant swamp and it sure felt like it.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/EaC1X04.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>At the end of July I attended the Fulbright Pre-Departure Orientation (PDO) in D]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Fulbright program" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/Fulbright-program/"/>
    
      <category term="group" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/group/"/>
    
      <category term="Update" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Update/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/07/09/first-post/"/>
    <id>http://nathanielray.com/blog/2015/07/09/first-post/</id>
    <published>2015-07-09T16:41:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-09T21:25:12.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dLWnVYq.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h1 id="Might_as_well_blog">Might as well blog</h1><p>It’s been a while since I’ve maintained a blog with any kind of regularity, but my upcoming Fulbright to Ukraine has prompted me to start up a new one. For those of you who, like my parents, would worry without any regular updates, look! You can get your updates here. And without the mass group email.</p>
<p>I’ll still be active on twitter, but this medium allows for longer posts with more pictures and stuff. Consider it a facebook replacement that you don’t have to feel obligated to like every post or picture I put up.</p>
<p>As far as the frequency of posts, I want to put up a new one every week or so, but I imagine that occasionally I won’t be in a place with reliable internet (or that I really just didn’t do anything interesting that week).</p>
<p>But if you want to contact me while I’m in Ukraine, you should check out the <a href="/about/index.html">About</a> page that has all my contact info.</p>
<p><em><small>The picture’s one I took when living in Ivano-Frankivsk in 2007</small></em></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dLWnVYq.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h1 id="Might_as_well_blog">Might as well blog</h1><p>It’s been a while since I’ve ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="Information" scheme="http://nathanielray.com/blog/categories/Information/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
